<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>Other Heaven</title>
      <link>https://otherheaven.net/</link>
      <description>Luther Gray&#x27;s personal site &amp; blog.</description>
      <generator>Zola</generator>
      <language>en</language>
      <atom:link href="https://otherheaven.net/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
      <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      <item>
          <title>Blockbench &#x27;Vertex Painting&#x27;</title>
          <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Luther Gray</author>
          <link>https://otherheaven.net/blog/blockbenchvertex/</link>
          <guid>https://otherheaven.net/blog/blockbenchvertex/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://otherheaven.net/blog/blockbenchvertex/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;ay-yo-wave&quot;&gt;Ay-Yo! 👋🏿&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am an ideas guy that has been hollowed out and contorted into the haunted and forlorn shape of a software developer. And there&#x27;s no further proof of that than my time spent architecting my Godot Resources. I thought that sentence sounded cool, but it&#x27;s not why I&#x27;ve arrived, groveling on my hands and knees before you today.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, it&#x27;s instead to address the sins I&#x27;ve long since ignored. The whispers of the Standards Demon in my ear.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&quot;Where is your flat lighting bro?&quot;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&#x27;t- I can&#x27;t do flat lighting.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&quot;Let your textures hang bro. What are you scared of? You have vertex colors to compensate.&quot;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I-...I-...!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&quot;You DO have Vertex Colors in your software of choice right bro? Or do you import your meshes from Blockbench into Blender to add those super critical components of the Lospec Aesthetic?&quot;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;we-used-to-beat-people-with-hammers&quot;&gt;We used to beat people with hammers!&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I&#x27;d be at the front of the line! I&#x27;ve been failing my Darkest Dungeon Sanity Checks every time I look at the Blender icon on my computer. I hate using Blender so much. It&#x27;s so convoluted when all I want to do it make my retro art.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s like a plumber having to go into a house with a toolshed on his back instead of just the same 4 tools on his belt and the same 8 fittings in his pocket.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;ve slowly become &lt;em&gt;that&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; kind of developer. I&#x27;ve grown to LOATHE complexity, and I strip it out of everything I can. That&#x27;s why I&#x27;m on Arch Linux (btw). It&#x27;s why my Minecraft Modlist nukes any mod that clogs my load order with yet another library that no one else uses. It&#x27;s why this very website has NO JavaScript. in its codebase.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was never truly a maximalist, but I was a minimalist. I swung back and forth on what I liked, but I&#x27;ve ended up as some strange, malformed creature that does both. In my physical, strong but mortally fragile meaty shell, I&#x27;ve grown to appreciate the aesthetic of clutter. It&#x27;s what brings personality to a space and a story to a home. But digitally, with my overly flowery words that have been spliced pixel by pixel with 1s and 0s, I HATE clutter.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So imagine my utter horror upon opening Autodesk Maya for the first time in college. I damn near fainted in my fucking seat! I slowly crawled my way back to life, like a fish that found the exact way to shuffle its body to bounce back into the sea. The key all along was just making a custom Shelf.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whew. Crisis Averted.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photoshop and pretty much every other &quot;Professional&quot; grade piece of software I&#x27;ve had the misfortune of being forced to use at gun-point, have had the same issue. Too many fucking buttons. I use 20 of them max and somehow there are 300 of these things.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One day, a couple of years after Graduating from University, I was about to go and update my &lt;strong&gt;legally aquired&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; copy of Autodesk Maya before snapping to the realization that I didn&#x27;t want to run on that treadmill forever. I wanted to rot and grow comfortable with a piece of software that would stay free and wouldn&#x27;t bend me over the barrel to use.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I already knew about Blender. When I was playing around with making cel-shaded lighting in Unreal Engine back then, Blender Tutorials are the only things that popped up on Youtube. No one could explain how it was done in a game, but everyone could tell you how to render it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;but-only-in-blender&quot;&gt;But only in Blender&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#x27;s an issue when it comes to the &quot;Professional&quot; space vs the Hobbyist space. All the super cool shit is where the Hobbyists are. Meanwhile those clowns on Polycount want to spend 2 hours arguing with you about why your blade of grass is 3 Tris instead of 1 Tri.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I knew I had to switch. The &quot;Professional&quot; world was fucking KILLING me. I hated every second of it. So I downloaded Blender, opened it up, picked the 3D General Template, and blacked out! 😊&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I swear it was like a light went off. I woke up covered in coffee and face down on my unvacuumed carpet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I was no coward. I learned to adapt. There was no shelf for me to use, but there was a small hidden menu called Favorites. I grabbed the same 10 fucking tools I use for literally everything, crammed them into the Favorites menu, changed my controls to Industry-Standard, removed as much of the UI as was reasonable and found peace.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nirvana.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 12 Chakras and 1000 Heavens. I attained peace. Until I tried making a pixel art texture, struggled with UV map warping and wanted to [REDACTED] myself with the longest [REDACTED] I could find.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;blockbench-my-beloved&quot;&gt;Blockbench my Beloved&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&#x27;t know it was Open-Source. Women will get mad at you because you took too long to meet them in their life, and I was mad at Blockbench because it had the nerve to hide away in the bowels of the Minecraft Community for some reason.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How many years had I wasted? That&#x27;s a question I never want to answer.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s here now though and things were never the same. Until I wanted to do Vertex Colors.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listen bro, the answer is Gradients. Okay? You lower the opacity, pick your UV Shell, Marqee or Wand Select what you need, then Gradient Black to White with a lower opacity. You can even do it on a new layer and Multiply it down at 70% Opacity.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, you didn&#x27;t even need Blockbench to do that. I can do it in Aseprite too. Look.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;blogImages&#x2F;VertexPaintDiff.png&quot; alt=&quot;VertexBrick&quot; title=&quot;See? I&amp;#39;m not crazy!&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which one has the fake lighting?! Oh god I can&#x27;t tell! 😲&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, I&#x27;m over it. Gotta get back to gushing about how cool my custom Godot Resources are and how they are better than yours.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bye Felica~ | Luther✌🏿&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>Figma Sucks, Use Penpot</title>
          <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Luther Gray</author>
          <link>https://otherheaven.net/blog/figmasucks/</link>
          <guid>https://otherheaven.net/blog/figmasucks/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://otherheaven.net/blog/figmasucks/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;hey-hey-wave&quot;&gt;Hey-hey 👋🏿&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember the first time a classmate in high-school sent me a Adobe XD file in our Graphic Design class to print out on the VERY expensive plastic label filter.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent all day downloading XD because my PC didn&#x27;t have it for some reason, and while I was doing that, I was reading the documentation for what it was, how it worked and why we should use it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, the answer is communication. As all things tend to be.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;once-upon-a-time&quot;&gt;Once Upon A Time&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you wanted to communicate your vision to a team, you would need to be an artist or an author. An artist can demonstrate their vision with pencil and paper. An author can construct an image within your head with the power of words alone.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, to get exactly what you want from a team of individuals, you MUST be able to communicate or demonstrate what it is that you want. Otherwise you&#x27;ll say things like my clients say.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;I want it to look like Facebook, except for the contacts, which should work like Twitter kinda.&quot;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;or&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Can you make it look like Overwatch, but low-poly like what you usually do?&quot;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;or even&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Something like Escape from Tarkov, but better.&quot;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, yes gotcha. Will do. Thanks bud, I&#x27;ll get right on it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could be a Carpenter you know? I could&#x27;ve been working with my hands. Making shit that mattered. But no-&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;communication-is-king&quot;&gt;Communication is King&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every relationship falls apart because communication sucked. Romantic and Professional. If the entire gist was to get your ideas across, then you could run into an issue where you are challenged in every way to tease that idea out of your head.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, with programmers in particular, they don&#x27;t have an artistic or yearning bone in their fucking bodies, so the challenge became systematic instead. Enter XD, Figma, and now Penpot.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fuck conveying an idea. These programs are used for one thing and one thing only, making a template. After you have a template and the pixel measurements associated with it, you can copy and paste that shit onto every page. This was before React blew up I think, so components and the idea of just abstracting from a component wasn&#x27;t up to snuff just yet. I don&#x27;t know that for sure because my brain was too smooth and I was scared to type hello world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This systematic method has become so extreme that now developers opt to use Tailwind to construct all their styles instead of hiring a Graphic Designer. And as AI becomes more of a thing, companies will choose to use AI to design their sites next.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AI is useful, but it&#x27;s not THAT useful. If you&#x27;ve read my previous posts already, you can probably tell why I think this is stupid. But if you haven&#x27;t, I&#x27;ll explain really quickly. You know how we&#x27;ve fallen into a corpo site massacre for websites these days? Everything looks the same? Standards have become overly strict?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, since AI can only do what it has seen before, what AI is trained to spit out, is more of these sites. More of these styles. More of these buttons. You&#x27;re not getting claymorphism from AI. Not like you haven&#x27;t seen done in those mockups I posted a while back.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For new aesthetics, new looks, new ideas, you NEED an artist. It&#x27;s not even a question. Some programmers I know, me included, are artists that have been strapped to the programmer table to pay the bills. You do what you gotta do. But the difference in what I breathe into front-end work is big enough for me to be asked to do more. I take that as a compliment, but also a warning.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Designers are essential. XD, Figma and Penpot in the hands of a programmer will give you shitty websites, just like books in the box of an AI will give you shitty penmanship. But that&#x27;s besides the point.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;anyways&quot;&gt;Anyways&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These programs are one particular feature of Photoshop cranked to 11 and rebuilt for web development. Snapping.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh my god there&#x27;s so much snapping. Global snapping, relational snapping, predictive snapping, GOSPEL SNAPPING! IT JUST DOESN&#x27;T END!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It even has &lt;strong&gt;MULTIPLAYER&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;! Yes, just like how Google Drive revolutionized the way we share and collab on documents, now you can collab on designs without DrawTogether!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This very site was originally designed in Penpot you know?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;blogImages&#x2F;penPot.png&quot; alt=&quot;LookLook&quot; title=&quot;Other Heaven&amp;#39;s Mockup!&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ahh, look at that. I started working on the card headers and footers then said &quot;fuck it&quot; and started doing whatever I wanted. It&#x27;s my site after all! I tinker, play, experiment, and throw weird shit at the wall for fun! I&#x27;ll change it later if I wanna, and I do all the time.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The industry standard for this kind of work is Figma, just like the industry standard for 3D work is Autodesk Maya. One may wonder why I&#x27;m on Penpot and not Figma. It&#x27;s because Penpot is open-source and self-hostable!~&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And also because Figma makes you pay 15 bucks a month to use Inspect Element on your site so you can copy and paste the HTML and CSS work. I&#x27;m a man that votes with my fucking wallet! If a service is doing something I don&#x27;t like, I just won&#x27;t pay! Simple! With Figma, I went to the next step of divesting from their platform all together.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;if-they-wanted-to-they-would&quot;&gt;If They Wanted To, They WOULD&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As someone who works in a company, I promise you that Companies do NOT care about you. No matter how good the social media presence, no matter how many hearts they put out in the weekly newsletter. You can be fucked up with no warning and even less recourse at their own discretion. You cannot have brand&#x2F;company loyalty today. It&#x27;s just a stupid thing to do. If they are publicly traded, they are evil.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In unrelated news, here&#x27;s Discord getting caught talking with bankers about going public on the stock market like Reddit did. -&amp;gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.nytimes.com&#x2F;2025&#x2F;03&#x2F;05&#x2F;technology&#x2F;discord-ipo.html&quot;&gt;Link&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&#x27;t trust companies, trust people. Wherever it&#x27;s reasonable for me to NOT use a company&#x27;s service, I will. But I work with collectives and independents all the time. Never had a terrible experience. The downside is that companies have capital. That money is a deal with the devil, so you have to trade off what&#x27;s important for you to function vs what&#x27;s important to your values. I dance on this balancing act pretty well and I&#x27;m not stressed about it because I&#x27;ve already moved so much off of platforms. Even this site is an expression of my will to be scrappy and slam shit together myself.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that&#x27;s all for a different blog post.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Figma is going the way of many big SaaS companies. They will do whatever they have to so that you pay that monthly sub, and forget about it. Even though most of their money comes from stabbing the pockets of other big businesses, they&#x27;ll fuck you, the consumer, no matter what. There&#x27;s no downsides after all.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you were looking for the alternative to Figma, it&#x27;s Penpot. Come on over. It&#x27;s not perfect, but it&#x27;s not as fucked as GIMP either. Trust me. :)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, I&#x27;m getting back to reworking some of my Roblox Animations.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chow(?)~ | Luther✌🏿&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>Scrapped Voxel Game</title>
          <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Luther Gray</author>
          <link>https://otherheaven.net/showcase/voxterra/</link>
          <guid>https://otherheaven.net/showcase/voxterra/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://otherheaven.net/showcase/voxterra/">&lt;p&gt;Next in line for my gaggle of destroyed and scrapped projects is Voxterra. Back when Cube World was basically nuked from orbit thanks to a horrible launch with more than questionable Game Design, I wanted to tinker around with the concept. I set up my player to have swappable pieces, once again making the folly of doing too much character art before making the actual fucking game~ :]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;portfolioImages&#x2F;voxPlayer.png&quot; alt=&quot;Scrapped Voxel Game&quot; title=&quot;Scrapped Voxel RPG&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Voxterra&#x27;s scope was very small, but I was already juggling far too many plates, in addition to learning Javascript so I could cleanly exit the gaming industry at the time and land on a soft cushion.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, it died before it could even walk. I still have the GDD for it laying around somewhere but it wasn&#x27;t detailed at all.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At one point I wanted to make a mod for Veloren to swap the player with this kind of Cube World-like character model instead of the defaults (I didn&#x27;t like them very much) but Veloren was written in RUST! HAHAHAHHAAHAHA! WHY? I DON&#x27;T KNOW! HAHAHAHAHAHAHAHA!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>Re-worked Pokemon Fan Game</title>
          <pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Luther Gray</author>
          <link>https://otherheaven.net/showcase/pkmnext/</link>
          <guid>https://otherheaven.net/showcase/pkmnext/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://otherheaven.net/showcase/pkmnext/">&lt;p&gt;When I was younger I made Pokemon Rom Hacks with random tools that I found on the internet. Before I started work on my own personal game, I thought that it&#x27;d be fun to make a HD-2D Pokemon Game in Godot.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then after I finished the first set of sprites, I choked.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;portfolioImages&#x2F;Player.png&quot; alt=&quot;Scrapped Pokemon&quot; title=&quot;Scrapped Pokemon Characters&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, I had a character creator feature planned. But the amount of sprites I would&#x27;ve had to make was overwhelming for me at the time. I think I made a simple walk cycle for the left and right directions, but then I pivoted.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My thinking was, well, I already know 3D. If I just make a character, I can swap the parts and do the character creation that way!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s worth noting that by this point, I didn&#x27;t know that Adobe bought Substance Painter. :]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;portfolioImages&#x2F;PlayerBB.png&quot; alt=&quot;Scrapped PokemonBB&quot; title=&quot;Scrapped Pokemon Character&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I promise you, I have gotten WAY better at making characters since then, but they still aren&#x27;t my strong suit.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a common issue with me and my projects for a long time.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recall reading that Miyamoto made sure that Mario was fun to move around in a 3D enviroment before he made a single level. I internalized that philosophy, and so a lot of my time is spent making characters and character controllers. They aren&#x27;t my strength, but I do them anyways because I NEED a character to make the rest of the world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Want to make a door? Well how big is the player? How fast do they move? Where is the camera? 1 million different questions that I can&#x27;t answer until I do it! It&#x27;s maddening!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is why people say don&#x27;t do indie development alone. Not because it&#x27;s particularly difficult, but because it&#x27;s time consuming as all hell.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, I still haven&#x27;t given up on this project, and I want to make it come to life eventually, but that&#x27;ll 100% be YEARS away.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>Scrapped Weapons</title>
          <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Luther Gray</author>
          <link>https://otherheaven.net/showcase/bladeworks/</link>
          <guid>https://otherheaven.net/showcase/bladeworks/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://otherheaven.net/showcase/bladeworks/">&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, I got added to a game jam (that we couldn&#x27;t finish in time. :] ) and someone brought up the idea of an evolving weapon. I drafted up a few sets. Since the project was scrapped, a lot of GDD work and art was thrown into the trash and it wasn&#x27;t until just now that I thought about dragging this stuff up from my hard drive.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;portfolioImages&#x2F;Swords.png&quot; alt=&quot;Blade Works&quot; title=&quot;Scrapped Weapons&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I might use some of them in projects later, probably after adapting them to 3D, but they were fun to sprite out as well~&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you couldn&#x27;t tell, yes it was VERY fun making that fan blade.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>The Existential Horrors of Vibe Coding</title>
          <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Luther Gray</author>
          <link>https://otherheaven.net/blog/vibehorrors/</link>
          <guid>https://otherheaven.net/blog/vibehorrors/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://otherheaven.net/blog/vibehorrors/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;aye-yo-wave&quot;&gt;Aye Yo~ 👋🏿&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you learn software of any kind, you begin to appreciate the process of becoming familiar with a codebase. When you work at a company, it&#x27;s very rare that you&#x27;ll be constructing the entire codebase from scratch. You weren&#x27;t there during its creation, your job is just to navigate its pathways, tracing the comments of the programmers who came before you.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&#x27;re lost at first, it&#x27;s as if you&#x27;ve been dropped into the depths of a foggy and overgrown forest. But as you pull on the vines to see if a snake drops out of the tree or a fruit, you begin to get a knack for what you&#x27;re seeing. You know where each function fits into the grand scheme of the project and when something breaks, you know every system that&#x27;s related to the error and can easily track the issue down.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s very human-like problem solving. Step by step. No stats, no complicated algorithms or deductionist principals. Just raw problem-solving.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;enter-ai&quot;&gt;Enter AI&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;ll repeat this until it&#x27;s no longer true.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AI is useful, but it is not THAT useful.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AI can do many different things, and in the hands of someone who understands what it&#x27;s doing, AI can boost your productivity by quite a lot. Imagine a world where you never have to write another piece of boilerplate when you make a new file? AI did that for you. But AI cannot problem-solve. It cannot find solutions to problems that it has not been trained on. AI will repeat what it&#x27;s seen before, and depending on the language you&#x27;re using, that can be a good thing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Javascript for example, runs the web. AI, no matter the company, is trained VERY well on Javascript. So well, that working with AI is like working with a Junior Dev in my experience. You have to slowly guide it to the right solutions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, unlike a Junior Dev, the AI will not remember what you taught it. You aren&#x27;t working with the training weights. You, as an AI user, are JUST a user. A Junior will grow as you train them. A tree given water and sunlight. Eventually, as you grow old and decrepit, a fossil with no reason to be brought back to life, the Junior will become a Senior and blame you for ruining the codebase-&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back on topic, so AI is useful for helping a developer that knows what they are doing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what if you &lt;em&gt;don&#x27;t know what you&#x27;re doing&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;youtu.be&#x2F;TN25ghkfgQA&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;VSauce Intrigue Music&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Play that music for as long as you&#x27;d like while reading.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;vibe-coding&quot;&gt;Vibe Coding&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#x27;s nothing more horrifying than watching an AI construct code from nothing, being prompted to fix a problem, and then re-writing half of the entire codebase while also not fixing the problem.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is no Junior Developer. They are too scared to touch code that they have not been explicitly told to touch. I leave a comment for my juniors at the top of the files I think they&#x27;ll need.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#x2F;&#x2F; This one is for you Tommy&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those of you not in the know, Vibe Coding was this term that suddenly popped up in programming circles and has since reached escape velocity. The entire thing is, you set up an AI with access to a portion of your filesystem or just your entire codebase, you prompt it with what you want, and &lt;strong&gt;no matter what it spits out&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, you just hit accept. Every single time. Don&#x27;t bother asking, don&#x27;t parse, don&#x27;t double check that it&#x27;s not breaking your carefully constructed feature. Accept what the AI does, sit back, and relax.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I say it has reached escape velocity, what I mean is people are using vibe coding in GAME DEVELOPMENT. That&#x27;s where this originated too. One of the shittiest games I have ever seen, but it charged people an upfront fee to play. And since the creator had a strong and avid following and could market very well, the game sold hotcakes. No steam means no 30% cut either. As you can imagine, when the sharks smell money, they come swimming for profits.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since AI cannot synthisize new solutions or make connections outside of its training, all it can do is paste code that its seen, not giving a fuck about the context of that code. Code can be written 1000 different ways. I can show you a web page without a single forloop, but then I&#x27;d get fired from my job, get my house burned down, and blacklisted from my contacts. AI will take that demon-spawn code and slap it in because it would technically solve the problem.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether the code runs or not is a problem for the developer to solve. And the Vibe Code way to deal with this is to just copy the error and paste it in the AI, then go back to watching Netflix. Rinse and Repeat, wasting money on tokens 30 times over until finally something works and you move on, uncaring that if the player double taps a button on the UI, the camera flips upside down.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hold my hands over my eyes and peek through my fingers when I watch someone who obviously couldn&#x27;t console.log their way out of a paper bag, slapping Cursor on their project and letting it commit coding war crimes. Of course they can&#x27;t use git, so all of this just-&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh man.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;a-breakthrough&quot;&gt;A Breakthrough&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what I &lt;em&gt;thought&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; would happen was that recursive thinking feature from a year ago or so right? The AI will ask itself, &quot;Hey, is this fucked?&quot; and it will reply to itself, &quot;Oh yeah, it is lol&quot;. When it spends 5x as long to double-check if it&#x27;s crazy, AI tends to output higher quality responses.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But as of right now, that doesn&#x27;t seem to make a dent in the fact that, fundementally, AI just is NOT ready to act like a Junior Dev yet. The horror of this entire thing comes in when a C-Suite Exec sees their son Vibe Coding the shittiest piece of software that the world has ever known, comes to work and says, &quot;Why the fuck are we hiring developers lol?&quot;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And you&#x27;d think that was a joke, but Shopify CEO, Tobi Lütke, told his team that they had to prove a job couldn&#x27;t be done with AI before asking for more people to be hired.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;blogImages&#x2F;vibeCode.png&quot; alt=&quot;Vibe Code&quot; title=&quot;Another reason to hate a CEO&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.theverge.com&#x2F;news&#x2F;644943&#x2F;shopify-ceo-memo-ai-hires-job&quot;&gt;Verge Article&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine being one of these poor sacks of shit. A developer that has to beg and plead, on their knees, for the company to stop pushing AI like it&#x27;s going to fucking save them.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel like stuff like this only blackpills people on the thought of working for companies more, but what choice do they have? If there&#x27;s a drop on their number chart, the entire business collapses. Being steady and crusing along, content to not chase profits, isn&#x27;t the way to succeed in business.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But despite knowing that, I still feel sick reading this because once again, AI isn&#x27;t that useful. Not yet. All of this shit before then is just ruining the process of coding. AI also ruins our ability to think but that&#x27;s a different discussion for a different day.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;ignore-the-10x-dev&quot;&gt;Ignore the 10x Dev&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&#x27;re always going to run into this type of developer who not only takes great pride in what they do, but they try to shame you if you don&#x27;t have the same amount of pride that they do. For these people, being a developer is their calling, the only thing in their lives that they truly care about or are good at. The 10x Developer will go on and on about how good AI is, but like I said above, AI is good because they know what they are doing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are Junior, or honestly, even Mid-Level, I highly advise against using AI. What seperates a Senior Dev from everyone else is their ability to make a problem and solve that problem without help from anyone else. That only comes from experience. The struggle is what makes you learn.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&#x27;t do it the 10x Developer way. That&#x27;s stupid, you have a family to feed, hobbies to engage in, friends to talk to, and a life to live. 85 on this planet and over 25 are already gone. Do you really want to sit here groveling to be a 10x Developer? There&#x27;s too much more to life than that buddy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s okay if you don&#x27;t want to understand C because you work a React job. It&#x27;s okay if you don&#x27;t really understand the underlying logic of a forLoop. It&#x27;s okay if you don&#x27;t want to practice the tenants of clean-code.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it&#x27;s also okay if you don&#x27;t want to learn AI. By time AI is ready to take your job, you&#x27;ll know it. And hopefully by then, you&#x27;ll have a healthy retirement saved up, and you can relax on a beach, sipping whatever the fuck you sip on a beach, and code fun projects that make sense. Work that muscle, not because the Shopify CEO wants 10x Devs and an army of AI arms attatched to their joints, but because making shit is fun.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Art, Coding, Learning in general is fucking fun.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#x27;s a Joy in Creation, and AI saps all of the life out of it. The horror is real, and the pool of people who understand what they are seeing is very small. No one is willing to listen. You alone can&#x27;t stem the tide. AI is here to stay and it won&#x27;t get good until the bubble pops.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take your time, don&#x27;t panic, don&#x27;t feel dread.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And don&#x27;t fucking Vibe Code.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take it easy~ | Luther✌🏿&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>Medic Mod</title>
          <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Luther Gray</author>
          <link>https://otherheaven.net/showcase/medic/</link>
          <guid>https://otherheaven.net/showcase/medic/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://otherheaven.net/showcase/medic/">&lt;p&gt;I play a lot of Minecraft, especially modded. I&#x27;ve always wanted to make my own pack on the Fabric modloader, but I didn&#x27;t have all the mods I needed to make it happen.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After months of oo-ing and aa-ing over the right version for me, I settled on 1.21 and went to work on my very first mod.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Java was hell and Gradle should burn in a pit far away from mortal eyes.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;modrinth.com&#x2F;mod&#x2F;medic!&#x2F;gallery&quot;&gt;Medic! on Modrinth&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;ve made a few mods since then, Tools of the Apoc and something else I have cooking up that I&#x27;m bug fixing now, but Roblox Development has distracted me a lot lol.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also the icon for Medic! was my first time speed sculpting in Blockbench. I did it a lot in Blender and Maya but those works will never see the light of day for as long as I live.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, enjoy the spinning medic crate that isn&#x27;t in the game.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;portfolioImages&#x2F;medicBox.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Medic!&quot; title=&quot;Medic Icon&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>Male Character Turnaround</title>
          <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Luther Gray</author>
          <link>https://otherheaven.net/showcase/maletemplate/</link>
          <guid>https://otherheaven.net/showcase/maletemplate/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://otherheaven.net/showcase/maletemplate/">&lt;p&gt;I made a blog post about this, but decided to make it its own page.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;blogImages&#x2F;maleTurnaround.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Male Turn Around&quot; title=&quot;Male Turnaround&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He even has fingers!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;blogImages&#x2F;heHasFingers.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;He Has Fingers!&quot; title=&quot;Male Model Examining New Fingers&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>Learning to Respect Roblox</title>
          <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Luther Gray</author>
          <link>https://otherheaven.net/blog/respectblox/</link>
          <guid>https://otherheaven.net/blog/respectblox/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://otherheaven.net/blog/respectblox/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;hey-hey-hey-wave&quot;&gt;Hey Hey Hey!👋🏿&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent a little bit of yesterday redesigning my hair and hat when some over-designed V-Tuber that wore over 23 different accessory pieces told me that I gotta lock the fuck in. So I said fine.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;blogImages&#x2F;Overdesigned.png&quot; alt=&quot;Blockbench Flashbang&quot; title=&quot;Blockbench Concept Work&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something I forgot the pain of was dreadlocks. There&#x27;s room to do something really cool there, but each strand is the temptation of just clapping your hands and saying it&#x27;s all good. I&#x27;ll explain the hat at another time when I start yapping about the game I&#x27;m working on in secret.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of many.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best thing about this base mesh that I finally got nailed down is that he&#x27;s way easier to pose and work with than my previous attempts. The character that&#x27;s on Other Heaven&#x27;s landing page doesn&#x27;t even have legs y&#x27;know?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or rather, he does, but they are literally just sticks so they may as well not exist.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#x27;t feel happy or professional enough to straight up give you the baseMesh, but here&#x27;s the turn around for you to trace over if you want. I have you a black outline to help its shape stand out when you turn the opacity down. (That&#x27;s something I struggled with a lot.)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;blogImages&#x2F;maleTurnaround.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Male Turn Around&quot; title=&quot;Male Turnaround&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you actually do want to use the model itself, just contact me and I&#x27;ll make it public for anyone to use. I&#x27;m not a character modeler so my confidence in it is really low lol&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He even has fingers!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;blogImages&#x2F;heHasFingers.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;He Has Fingers!&quot; title=&quot;Male Model Examining New Fingers&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the face, I highly suggest you use 2D Textures on a plane for the eyes, then again for the mouth. It will help you make expressions and such later on with a facial rig. Even if you&#x27;re not animating, if you want to take screenshots and pose, it&#x27;s a pain in the ass to disable the happyEyes layer and enable the sadEyes layer over and over.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&#x27;s a couple of vids on how that happens in both Blender and Blockbench. Basically you&#x27;re going to keyframe UV positions to switch between expressions. I really ought to write that stuff down eventually so when the heat death of the internet comes and all the data rots, I&#x27;ll still have these videos in a different form.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;youtu.be&#x2F;MmMJuuX5Ago&quot;&gt;BLOCKBENCH - From the Fantastical, MisterGriimm!&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;youtu.be&#x2F;VZYm4mg1Eyo&quot;&gt;BLENDER - From MY BOY WIZ!&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, enjoy or whatever.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;novice&quot;&gt;Novice&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine came to me recently telling me that he wanted to make video games and I tried to narrow down exactly what he wanted to do in game development. The answer was inconclusive.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coincidentally, at the time, RPGMaker VXAce was FREE on steam. I 100% endorse RPG Maker as an gateway drug into the hellish life of game development.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those of you who aren&#x27;t too familiar, RPG Maker is like Scratch but for Video Games. It gives you a bunch of pre-made tooling, everything you need to make a game from beginning to end, and then you can click and drag everything you need from there.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I refer to RPG Maker as the engine that you don&#x27;t need a keyboard to use. It&#x27;s that simple.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though the name is RPG Maker, you can twist that engine to make many different things, from FPS Dungeon Crawls, to Action-Heavy Zelda Likes. The real limitation is 3D, but you can fake it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those out of bounds ambitions are going to be what wil start to bug you. RPG Maker is great at what it does, but when you try to leave the sandbox it made, you&#x27;re going to crawl through glass. So much so that if the time you spent trying to bend RPG Maker to your whims was used to follow a Godot tutorial, the RPG Maker method would&#x27;ve taken you 3x as long.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel confident enough in saying that to put money down on it. If you want to make a dungeon crawler, you CAN do it with RPG Maker, but I&#x27;m begging you to use Godot instead. You&#x27;ll save yourself SO much headache.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;first-test&quot;&gt;First Test&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I gave my friend a simple test. A list of objectives to complete to get a feel for what he liked and what he didn&#x27;t.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a Chest with a Potion in it.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make the potion kill you when you drink it.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change a Dialog Box.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a house and go into that house.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These seemed like reasonable goals in my head. Each one escalating in difficulty. It touches on everything except for UI Design, but one could argue that learning UI is like learning Graphic Design. For the sake of making games, this usually isn&#x27;t what people think of. It&#x27;s incredibly important, but it&#x27;s not the fantasy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, he got to the Dialog Box before bringing up to me that the game he wanted to make was an FPS Squad Shooter, not an RPG.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I was a shittier friend, maybe I would&#x27;ve said &quot;You need to spend 8000 hours grinding pong game design before you can make your dream game&quot; but I&#x27;m not an idiot. What gets a game done is less skill and more enthusiasm. Even after you spend time grinding out the fundamentals, it can make the road to your dream game smoother, but in the end you still wasted time making shit that you didn&#x27;t want to make.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your enthusiasm is lesser and as a result, when you finally DO sit down for your dream game, you are 20 years late.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fuck that.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have an open-world survival mmorpg that mixes every single genre under the sun as your dream game, chase it! Don&#x27;t let anyone tell you otherwise! Fly close to the sun and feel how it singes your skin! Fuck these guys out here telling you to take it slow! 80 Years on this planet and 20 are already gone! Get your ass in there!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I knocked the idea around. Regardless of if this was true passion or just the fantasy of Game Development that a lot of players get in their head, I wanted to cater to that. I had time to kill and this was my friend so I thought it over.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I came to a startling realization. Didn&#x27;t I already have a platform, one that I grew up playing on, that could help him make his game in a realistic amount of time? Without learning server-client deliniation or a dab of scripting? One that had a co-op development enviroment so that I could work along-side him in real time?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;sorry-roblox-i-didn-t-respect-your-game&quot;&gt;Sorry Roblox, I didn&#x27;t respect your game!&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was a fool! This &quot;Children&#x27;s Platform&quot; nonsense has to fucking END! Roblox Studio is a straight up, real deal, big dick, no frills, LUA ENGINE.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It didn&#x27;t take me long to realize that after we got in. Brother you will not believe the horrors I&#x27;ve had to deal with fighting against Roblox.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like RPG Maker, Roblox technically gives you a bunch of pieces in the sandbox to play with, but while RPG Maker told you to play with the toys in the sandbox, Roblox flies you out to the Sahara Desert in a rickety-dull gray military plane, kicks you out the hangar door with a parachute and a bag of sandbox toys.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did NOT know they were playin like this. I used to clown this platform for the same reason people clowned Melee, Minecraft, or Video Games in general! &quot;Isn&#x27;t that for kids?&quot; I WAS A FOOL! FORGIVE ME!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like, everything from UI to Physics is in this engine and need to be aknowledged at least a bit to make ANY game. This is the engine for Junior Developers and if I used Roblox Studio before I learned Unreal Engine in college, I would&#x27;ve had a FAR easier time.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All I remember doing in 2008 was playing those obby courses. I stopped playing when I was 15 or something I think. Since then, Roblox has changed like CRAZY. You can even change out the view models with realistic Blender sculpts!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, I plopped my friend in, dusted off my old account, and now we&#x27;re putting together his squad shooter fps game that has now morphed into a sci-fi extraction shooter with demons. It&#x27;s fun to see how he thinks through problems and digs up solutions using the experience he had playing other games. I&#x27;m still here to keep the wheels on the bike and make sure the game loop doesn&#x27;t expand before it&#x27;s solid, but for the most part, I&#x27;m letting him run wild.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want the scope to creep up past this marker that I set,  and while I enforce that we develop within the scope, the longer he looks at all that shit he has left to do.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ambition is the first nail I want to hammer into his hands.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second nail is time spent doing shit that doesn&#x27;t contribute to the gameplay, but is critical for anything else to work.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also taught him to use PenPot, a Figma alternative, to start designing the UI.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Might even drag a few more friends into the fold to make him take charge as the team lead and point at a direction that he doesn&#x27;t know how to navigate.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of these parts are growth points, and the pain of burning in the sun&#x27;s rays and letting the glue of your wings melt are important when it comes to forging a stronger will and ambition.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cowards who spend 20 years making games they wouldn&#x27;t ever play don&#x27;t learn this until it&#x27;s too late.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roblox is the perfect enviroment to explore all of these pain points, because I can literally script through any problem when he struggles. Of course, there&#x27;s gotta be times when I lie and say &quot;Yeah idk how to do that lol&quot; so he can navigate the lack of expertise, but the entire exercise we&#x27;re going through here is really enjoyable.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I might just like teaching idk.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, I&#x27;m gonna fix the momentum issues in our playerController script because Roblox doesn&#x27;t have Acceleration. They instantly snap from 0 to max speed, which doesn&#x27;t feel good in first person.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deuces~ | Luther✌🏿&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>Local Kanye West Fan in SHAMBLES</title>
          <pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Luther Gray</author>
          <link>https://otherheaven.net/blog/localkanyefan/</link>
          <guid>https://otherheaven.net/blog/localkanyefan/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://otherheaven.net/blog/localkanyefan/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hip-Hop Culture Heavy Post Ahead&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;ahhhhhhhhhh-what-is-he-doing-and-hi-lol-wave&quot;&gt;AHHHHHHHHHH WHAT IS HE DOING?! &lt;em&gt;and hi lol&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; 👋🏿&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#x27;s a tradition you go through when Kanye West is your goat. Every other year, the entire hip-hop community gets to point and laugh at you as the world watches your goat crash the fuck out. It&#x27;s a humiliation ritual, a universal hazing that surpasses the absolute devastation that is Carti fans waiting 5 years for yet ANOTHER mid album, Drake fans sweating their asses off trying to defend this guy from xyz allegation&#x2F;Karen-ass move, and Cole fans swearing up and down that their goat was just playin around with that grippy bar.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wake up in a cold sweat every morning, whisper a &quot;he made Graduation&quot; prayer to no one in particular, check my phone and then collapse into a pile of fucking ash, like a vampire exposed to sunlight. I&#x27;m not showing these tweets because I already get laughed at enough by people &lt;strong&gt;in&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; the hip-hop community.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I DON&#x27;T NEED MORE PEOPLE TO POINT AND LAUGH!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;just-change-your-g-o-a-t-lol&quot;&gt;Just change your G.O.A.T lol&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YOU DON&#x27;T THINK I&#x27;VE TRIED?! No one has that catalogue like Kanye does man! Kendrick crawls out of the shadows for a full album every half decade. JID only has 3 full albums, everything else is a feature (he slaps but it&#x27;s just the one feature!). Tyler is crazy fantastic, but also crazy experimental. A$AP Rocky basically retired after he snatched up Rihanna. Frank Ocean wants all his fans to FUCKING DIE. Earl- Oh god.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically what I&#x27;m saying is that Kenny Mason is my last hope and if that doesn&#x27;t work out I&#x27;m just gonna fucking [REDACTED].&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why can&#x27;t Kanye just chill tf out man?! What&#x27;s up with this guy?! We were all in a better place when he was banned on Twitter I swear! NEVER should&#x27;ve let this guy back into the gates!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just need one more. One more good record then I can wash my hands of this mf for GOOD. Donda wasn&#x27;t closure. Just one more time I need this guy to get his shit together and prove that he was trolling ever since &lt;em&gt;Jesus Is King&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. You don&#x27;t know what it&#x27;s like to be a stan of a crazy bastard like this one! I&#x27;m trapped in hell! HE MADE GRAADUATION, COME ON MAN!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;luther-i-want-to-tell-you-my-favorite-artist-now&quot;&gt;&quot;Luther I want to tell you MY favorite artist now!&quot;&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know I thought about adding a guestbook&#x2F;comment section just recently, but now I&#x27;m sitting here rubbing my chin like- &quot;Naahhhhh, that&#x27;s not a good fucking idea buddy!&quot; Some nasty rat will skitter in, sniffling-&quot;Have you listened to that new PartyNextDoor?&quot; &quot;Hey man, what about Future, I saw DS2 on your scroll bro. Come on bro. Can&#x27;t trust these hoooooeeees bro.&quot;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You and I, we&#x27;re cordial. Y&#x27;know? Author and reader. We have a harmonious relationship that transcends time and space. You wouldn&#x27;t want to throw that away just to tell me, &quot;Actually, I thought Whole Lotta Mid was great! And that new thang? I Am Music? &lt;em&gt;chef kiss&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&quot;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&#x27;s get along to get along. You have the worst taste imaginable, and I have to crawl on my hands and knees, nose to the fucking ground, begging and pleading like a worthless slug drowning in salt, &quot;Kanye does not speak for black people please don&#x27;t listen to this guy!&quot;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#x27;re similar in that way, aren&#x27;t we? Yeah, I agree. &lt;strong&gt;WE&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; are in the same boat.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We used to have good times. Before he said he wanted to buy a tank and started parading his 4th wife around naked on broadway. That documentary came out and had everyone on his side for a bit and dissing the hell out of Jay-Z. I could go to sleep smiling. I could talk about my musical tastes while I was on a date and get a smile of respect. Sure I didn&#x27;t like JPEG Mafia, but Kanye was a reasonable pick! A classic!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everytime I started to feel down, I looked at Drake fans watching their mans destroy the culture in real time and nodded my head in satisfaction. &quot;Good.&quot; I&#x27;d say to myself, chuckling because while their goat made one hit, Scorpion, he was never consistent. I could end every single argument with &quot;Dog, your goat is Drake. Sit the fuck down lol&quot;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then Kanye tweets, I get pinged, and-&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Shocking New Development! Local Black Man Found In A Catatonic State After Kanye West Defends Hitler, AGAIN!&quot;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&#x27;t win! JUST GIVE ME ONE MORE! ONE MORE GOOD RECORD! I KNOW YOU CAN! QUIT PLAYIN! I FEEL LIKE A GAMBLER WITH A HOLE IN HIS POCKET! I CAN&#x27;T LOSE AGAIN CAN I?! SURELY I CAN GET A FUCKING WIN! GIMMIE A WIN! MAKE THE PAIN STOP! BAN THIS ASSHOLE FROM TWITTER! TAKE AWAY THE NITROUS! WHO IS HIS HANDLER?! SOMEONE GET HIM! HAHAHAHAHAHAHAHAHA FUCK!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Horrific vibes~ | Luther&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>The Programmer to Carpenter Pipeline</title>
          <pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Luther Gray</author>
          <link>https://otherheaven.net/blog/programmertocarpenter/</link>
          <guid>https://otherheaven.net/blog/programmertocarpenter/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://otherheaven.net/blog/programmertocarpenter/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;my-guy-sup-wave&quot;&gt;My guy....Sup. 👋🏿&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before he passed, my dad used to say that people who worked with their minds relaxed with their hands. And I took that personally. It&#x27;s 100% true.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#x27;s a particular type of hand relaxing that youtubers do, especially when they think they camera&#x27;s aren&#x27;t rolling and it&#x27;s not what you&#x27;re thinking about.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The name they have for this profession is, Maker.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a sterile and annoyingly accurate name for the craft.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3D Printing, Woodworking, Metalworking, CAD Software, Electronics, Welding, Blacksmithing, CNC Machining, Leatherworking, Ricing, all of these things that I could take out of a skill book in Runescape fall into that disgusting bucket that we call Maker. But what else were we gonna call it???&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Engineers, Craftsmen, Creatives, and Artists be damned! You&#x27;re a Maker now!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#x27;s something almost transecndant about sitting down in front of &lt;em&gt;insert creative project here&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; and slowly chipping away at not only the material, but also your lifespan. It&#x27;s Magical.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zen.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meditative.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost like you should be using a power tool instead of the hand tools that the old guy at the wood supply shop said you &quot;HAVE&quot; to use. But you know what? That old guy is right. Not about that rant about not being able to trust your wife, but about using hand tools.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#x27;re relaxing with your hands, doesn&#x27;t it make sense to wither away on your project? Eternally taking time to measure that cut on your band saw that you just can&#x27;t bring yourself to make?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Oh but the wood is so expensive!&quot;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&#x27;s the excuse I use, write your favorite in the comments.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;That was a joke, there are no comments.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Occasionally during this time of relaxation, I have to wait on xyz process to complete. Leather that needs to soak overnight. Glue that needs to dry... overnight. Concrete that needs to cure...damn man it take&#x27;s a while innit?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;dreams-of-industry&quot;&gt;Dreams of Industry&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this time, when I stare languidly at the ceiling, pondering the important questions in life, like why that guy really didn&#x27;t like his wife, I occasionally ask myself how I ended up in the position where I rolled out of bed on my day off, to do manual labor. I have friends that would kill for a cushy work from home or cubical hell office job. And then, there I was, daydreaming about sharing sandwiches with the boys on a jobsite. Asking some guy named Benny if he secured the joist.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I do not know what that means but it sounds cool.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting yelled at by our supervisor for slacking off and reminding us that there&#x27;s a housing crisis and if we don&#x27;t finish this bid in 4 months, even at the cost of the house&#x27;s structrual integrity, that we could lose our job to the &lt;em&gt;gasp&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; Mexicans?!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sudden stress snaps me out of the romance of sharing a sandwich with the boys and back into planning the 18th side project that I need for my main project to actually function.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I watch a more than one machinist on Youtube and half of his entire schtick is that he&#x27;s stuck in a side project that&#x27;s a branch of a side project. An eternal hell composed of copper stock and tool steel. Another 2mm difference that&#x27;s caused by gravity&#x27;s shackles pulling down on the stock. Another cutting tip, torn apart by rotational forces that one could mistake for a ever consuming black hole. The maw of machinery that threatens to steal the limbs of anyone who comes close.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any red blooded man making jokes at his wife&#x27;s expense will tell you, you MUST respect your tools in the shop. The day you go in, doing something you&#x27;ve done 2000 times before, is the day you lose something that you can never get back. Why can&#x27;t they just say they cut off their finger doing a routine cut? Why does it have to be so fucking dramatic?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;ve been scared straight for sure. There&#x27;s a list of machines that I will never ever buy, and I&#x27;d consider it an attack on me if anyone tried to force me. You don&#x27;t want to see Luther&#x27;s Self Defense in action when you get me too close to the jointer. Table saw? More like, Stop That, or something. Router? Nah, I think I&#x27;ll just sand that down. Angle Grinder? Idk it doesn&#x27;t look bad, but I hear horror stories about the sparks flying around full face shields so I guess I just won&#x27;t.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#x27;s a lesson somewhere in there that&#x27;s like, be brave. Use the dangerous power tools. Leave your primitive ways behind.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-about-no&quot;&gt;How about, No?&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#x27;s a consequence to growing up in the generation that&#x27;s been exposed to the internet before the safety rails were put on. Though, you could argue that even now, the internet is still the wild west, I&#x27;ve been exposed to horrific things that a normal civilian of a first world country would not normally see! Oh joy! I won&#x27;t describe this stuff or the webring will take me for my foams, but I&#x27;m plenty aware of how bad things can go.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For something that&#x27;s supposed to just be my method of relaxation and zen rather than a business where I&#x27;m being paid tens of thousands of dollars to make yet another fucking epoxy table, that trade off just ain&#x27;t worth it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I say all of that, but then I only recently found out that you&#x27;re not supposed to be breathing in those solder fumes. So who am I to talk?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yo, check this out -&amp;gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;blogImages&#x2F;purpleHeart.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Purple Heart&quot; title=&quot;Some Purple Heart Wood&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isn&#x27;t it pretty? That is one of my favorite types of wood right there. Purple Heart. It&#x27;s purple now, but it gradually fades into a distinct and dark Walnut shade over time as it&#x27;s exposed to air.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think there was a type of sealant you could use to keep it purple for longer, but eventually it will turn back into normal colored wood. Whenever I run into an issue during work, like a div not centering because I mistyped the class name, or when a project hits a brick wall because it&#x27;s using a dependancy for some old ass and not updated plugin that makes graphs, or when I have to look at code that Prettier can&#x27;t format correctly, my mind flashes to Purple Heart Wood.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like a trauma response.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I feel calm. I know that after I recommend a complete and total rewrite of this project for the 10th time and get told that it&#x27;s not worth it because the amount of time we&#x27;d save starting over couldn&#x27;t be the same as the amount of time we spend parsing through unformatted PHP, I can come home and look at this wood on my 1440p monitor.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because wood is too fucking expensive.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn&#x27;t even the worst one.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;blogImages&#x2F;ebony.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ebony&quot; title=&quot;Ebony Wood&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wood, from the Million Dollar Tree. Ebony. I saw the price for a plank of this and my soul directly walked out of my body. He put on his hat, grabbed his suitcase and said he was going to the store for some cigarettes. There&#x27;s no fucking way it&#x27;s 600 bucks for &lt;strong&gt;1 BOARD&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know my place. I respect the price. They aren&#x27;t wringing that cash out of &lt;em&gt;my&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; ass. Let some other chump get caught out over some black wood.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;m black enough, &lt;em&gt;thank you very much&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, my friend insists that 3D printing is the future after showing me some of the ugliest and most layerlined models I have ever seen in my fucking life.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;You just gotta sand it bro.&quot;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After I inhale even more microplastics that will make the valves of my heart stutter and die, I will still be hovering over my 3D printed mess, using a bit of sandpaper on a stick to get inbetween the worst creases and crevices since Jason tried to stuff that body into a suitcase.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I&#x27;ll get fed up and try to use a Dremel, but the RPM will be too high and I&#x27;ll sand right through the fucking surface into the gritty and melted ABS on the inside.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or I could Resin Print. Using GALLONS of Iso Alcohol to clean the god damned things, and then I can put them on my shelf and stare at them as they gather dust.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Oh what&#x27;s that? A Funko Pop?&quot;
&quot;N-No... it&#x27;s &lt;em&gt;a Grey Knight from W-&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&quot;
&quot;A what now? Is that a new Funko Pop?&quot;
&quot;Y-Yeah. It is.&quot;
&quot;Wow, what a &lt;em&gt;loser&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;!&quot;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&#x27;t win!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could yap about this forever, but I don&#x27;t wanna.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, I have a Gregtech modpack to finish up and then I want to actually do a Rustlings exercise because I&#x27;ve slacked off like hell on that. Also chains are expensive as hell bro I might just put some sandbags on my weights and call it good.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take it easy~ | Luther✌🏿&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>Dead Graphic Design Trends</title>
          <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Luther Gray</author>
          <link>https://otherheaven.net/blog/deadgraphics/</link>
          <guid>https://otherheaven.net/blog/deadgraphics/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://otherheaven.net/blog/deadgraphics/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;wave-yowdy&quot;&gt;👋🏿 Yowdy!&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I&#x27;m not a Graphic Designer, but I touch on a lot of the same technologies in my work and hobbies. As a result, &lt;em&gt;eventually&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; I do pickup on hot trends &lt;em&gt;like half a decade later&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. I wanna yap about some of those trends and why I found them so interesting for a bit.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, let&#x27;s talk about something that popped up around 4 years ago and then died within half a year.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;neumorphism&quot;&gt;Neumorphism&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;blogImages&#x2F;neumorphic.png&quot; alt=&quot;Neumorphism&quot; title=&quot;Neumorphic Example&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was a youngin&#x27; I had a toy that had buttons that looked like this. I hated them with a passion. They never felt satisfying to push, the weird rubberized coating that kept the button &quot;sealed in&quot; would become dry and start tearing, and it just couldn&#x27;t match the feel of a good Gamecube Controller.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But as I grow older, I&#x27;ve learned to enjoy the little things in life. The subtleties that make things go round and tend to go unnoticed. I appreciate the mouth-feel of a piece of candy and notice when it doesn&#x27;t threaten to pull out my tooth fillings. I like the comforts of a soft fabric that doesn&#x27;t clog my dryer&#x27;s lint filter. The clunk of a well weighted mechanical keyboard and the click of my co-worker&#x27;s cherry mx blues that I&#x27;m &lt;em&gt;this close&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; to [[REDACTED]]. This extends from my taste in women to my taste in tea, and I wouldn&#x27;t have it any other way.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neumorphism is a sampling of subtle design that stems from the idea that everything is shrink wrapped in some matte colored fetish plastic. I&#x27;m 100% sure that&#x27;s what the original creator was thinking when they played around a bit too much in Figma and popped out the otherside with this. It&#x27;s obviously the consequence of someone who didn&#x27;t delete their DeviantArt account in time for the corpo takeover. The effect is actually created with the clever use of at least 2 shadows. 3 if you want the hard edge on top of some elements.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is there a meta narrative here that talks about the importance that we are increasingly placing on being authentic and tactile design like this is an expression of the deeper human psyche and need to become truly connected within a world that is evermore divided and schismed into camps that in another time could&#x27;ve grown to love each other? Maybe, but you didn&#x27;t hear it from me, okay?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;blogImages&#x2F;neumorphic2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Neumorphism_2&quot; title=&quot;Neumorphic Example 2&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nice. Nifty. Oh my god, it even has a watermark!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#x27;ve ever seen one of those touch devices where the buttons vibrate as you activate them to assure you that, yes this thing &lt;strong&gt;IS&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; on, the feeling I get is very similar to that. I try not to speak like an artist too much because even I get sick of being told to absorb the colors of a space and indulge in the creamy whites and pleasantly soft shadows that dance along the something something this or that. All I&#x27;m trying to say is that Neumorphism is either a fetish or a bad trip to Dubai.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take your pick.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;claymorphism&quot;&gt;Claymorphism&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;blogImages&#x2F;clayPeople.png&quot; alt=&quot;Clay People&quot; title=&quot;Claymorphism Example 0&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the artists who brought you the most disgusting looking characters in UI design that have plagued the mind of the average internet surfer for the past 10 years and shortened my lifespan almost as much as it has shortened my hairline, I&#x27;m proud to present to you-&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Claymorphism!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;blogImages&#x2F;claymorphism.png&quot; alt=&quot;Claymorphism&quot; title=&quot;Claymorphism Example&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, claymorphism is a Fisker Gone Wild party. The buttons aren&#x27;t rounded, they are &lt;strong&gt;ROUNDED&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. The shadows and highlights reach out like they are trying to snatch the font off the button. Everything is overly rounded, so much so that if I turned this in to my teacher at Full Sail, that fucker would&#x27;ve failed me without blinking. Unlike Neumorphism which is a latex fetish given credibility and a nice coat of paint, Claymorphism hovers off the screen like the floor is lava.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Claymorphism just goes to show that art truly is subjective, and no matter what your teacher said, stick figures are perfectly viable methods of characterization and deserve to stand alongside every other art technique like Chicken Scratch and accidentally dropping your canvas in the studio, which no one ever cleans before they fucking leave, so now it&#x27;s covered in dust and unsalvageable. Nothing about stick men are gaslighting and I don&#x27;t like buzzwords like that.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get a fucking grip.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;blogImages&#x2F;claymorphismCompared.png&quot; alt=&quot;ClaymorphismCompared&quot; title=&quot;Claymorphism Compared to Neumorphism&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, you can fool yourself into thinking this is cool, but the more you look at it...I don&#x27;t know, there&#x27;s just something so...inconsistent about Claymorphism in action, y&#x27;know? Is it just me?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look at that credit card example again. The difference in &lt;strong&gt;ROUNDED&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; percentage is about the same between the elements, but it&#x27;s struggling far more on the smaller components than the bigger ones. But having multiple sizes is an important part of the Graphic Design principal of Hierarchy, or so I&#x27;m told. When the buttons are so small that the shadows start to touch the highlights in such a way that I could put them behind bars for it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It doesn&#x27;t help that the page isn&#x27;t exactly leaning super hard into the style. So I&#x27;ll get another example for us, okay? Don&#x27;t move. I&#x27;ll be right back.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;blogImages&#x2F;clayExample3.png&quot; alt=&quot;Claymorphism3&quot; title=&quot;Claymorphism Example 3&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once again, at first, this is sick isn&#x27;t it? It&#x27;s like 😆, but then you give it like 10 minutes of thought and all of the sudden, 😷.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that&#x27;s the issue with playful UI. It is fun and enjoyable, but quickly you reach this point where you aren&#x27;t charmed any longer and it becomes gross to look at. I&#x27;m not posting that Grubhub commercial but you know exactly what I&#x27;m talking about right?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There has to be a middleground between the tactile feel of Neumorphism and the playful pop of Claymorphism. If only a multi-national conglomerate with billions and billions of dollars had backed a particualr UI style in house that combined the strengths of these two abandoned styles.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunatly, it doesn&#x27;t exist.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, cya~ | Luther&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;fluent-illustrations&quot;&gt;Fluent Illustrations&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;blogImages&#x2F;fluentIll.png&quot; alt=&quot;Fluent Illustrations&quot; title=&quot;Thanks Microsoft&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you say, Thank You Microsoft? Come on! All together let&#x27;s thank the multi-national conglomerate has has commited some of the worst crimes against software, locked the world into their bloated and dangerously unoptomized Operating Systems, lobbied against solutions that create a free and open internet for anyone and everyone, and now get on their hands and knees to tell users that their AI is useful and shouldn&#x27;t be forgotten after they poured billions of dollars into infastructure and service fees.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;thank-you-microsoft&quot;&gt;Thank you, Microsoft!!!&lt;&#x2F;h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;whistle&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was me whistling.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isn&#x27;t this nice? We have the tactile and intergrated feel of shrink-wrapped buttons. The rounded and extended shadows of clay. There are no outlines, just shade and contrast. The icons sit on some type of shelf, content to exist on their own. This is the methodology behind a LOT of Microsoft&#x27;s Fluent Design. It&#x27;s &quot;together&quot; the same way that your dad spending most of his time in the shed is &quot;together&quot;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It doesn&#x27;t repeat, it echoes. I think my favorite part of this is the texture work. Not only is it rather sparse, but it&#x27;s this strange glitter-doodle bug aesthetic that&#x27;s mixed with that one asshole kid in your class who kept mixing up all the fucking clay and so now no one can use just normal red clay, they have to use the red x blue x purple x brown clay.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Could&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; you do this with just CSS? Sure. Anything can be done with JUST CSS. But should you? Of course not! That&#x27;d be crazy! These icons are basically 3D renders. Extruded faces that had a couple point-lights shown on them from key angles. The best part of this is that it&#x27;s not getting old for me. I could stare at this all day, and I don&#x27;t think that&#x27;s because I&#x27;m Wallace &amp;amp; Gromit starved over here.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the key thing it was missing was texture. And now I keep throwing the question around in my head, did we really land on the moon? And then the other question, what would a full GTK or QT interface look like when every single element looked like this?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just got done being strung along like a dog on a leash by this fantastic youtuber named &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;@liber-indigo&quot;&gt;Liber-Indigo&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Spoilers for his Affordance of Magic series, but in the end he smokes enough whatever-the-hell to come up with Gravitational UI. Something like a mindmap that can be navigated with tabs and references.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;m also keeping my eye on a cool piece of software called &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;TagStudioDev&#x2F;TagStudio&quot;&gt;Tag Studio&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. It has a booru tagging system for your files and though it&#x27;s early days, it looks very interesting. They have 3D preview functionality on the way.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also saw this guy named &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=5eGUIsppX_8&quot;&gt;EJFox&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; make a virtual memory palace to manage his files and documents in VR. He can pick up the files and website links like cards, throw them around, link them with wires, and it&#x27;s all very physical.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why did I bring all of these things up at the same time?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dunno, anyways I got nothing to do.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peace~ | Luther✌🏿&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>The Dirty 3D Artist</title>
          <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Luther Gray</author>
          <link>https://otherheaven.net/blog/dirtyartist/</link>
          <guid>https://otherheaven.net/blog/dirtyartist/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://otherheaven.net/blog/dirtyartist/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;wave-ai-is-useful-but-not-that-useful&quot;&gt;👋🏿 AI is Useful, but not THAT Useful&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My friend group is small, but very diverse. It&#x27;s composed of a nasty mix of a doctor, lawyers, artists, programmers, gamers, designers, fashionistas, and 1 lone musician. As a digusting hybrid breed of artist, programmer, gamer and designer, I end up cross-pollinating, like a coked out bee, a lot of discussions when it comes to the thing that threatens everyone&#x27;s job.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AI.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what I say, everytime the topic comes up is, &quot;AI is useful, this is true, but it is not THAT useful.&quot; I&#x27;m saying that again now to really drive home that, AI is percieved to be more useful than it actually is, and when the bubble pops, that&#x27;s when we&#x27;ll likely see it&#x27;s true colors and use-cases come to the forefront. Those true colors have already shown glimmers of themselves here and there, and I think that we&#x27;ve already crossed the boundary of when we could have stopped these technologies from growing any further.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The genie has escaped from its lamp, and it said it&#x27;s never going back.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LLMs (Large Language Models) are suped up auto-corrects. They&#x27;ve trained on a lot of data, pretty much everything that the internet and even the world at large has committed to paper and ink. It&#x27;s like rule34 in a way. If your 3rd grade poem about daisies was uploaded onto the internet at some point before you became privacy consious, I assure you, that one of the many models out there has trained on it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a blessing and a curse for AI as, because they&#x27;ve trained on everything that&#x27;s come before, whenever you try to present it with a brand new problem, it eats shit. Try it yourself. Work with AI as a co-writer for some world lore. Or try to use AI as your co-pilot when coding. Listen to some AI music. Ask it to draw something unique in a style you&#x27;ve never heard of. These limits are easily bypassed by the human mind, but the prediction machine struggles and thrashes against its constraints. You&#x27;ll run into wall after wall. It&#x27;ll forget what you asked it to do, it will lie to your face about an assured answer, it will fabricate facts to turn your no into a yes.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AI is useful for learning concepts from books. It&#x27;s great at summarizing articles. It can teach you super position better than reading the Wikipedia page can. But it cannot synthsize. Not yet anyways. It&#x27;s just not at that point. However, make no mistake-&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One day, it will. One day, most likely within our lifetimes, AI will learn to learn. Not necessarily into AGI, but something similar most likely.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I say all of that to say-&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;genie-on-the-run&quot;&gt;Genie on the Run&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I cannot begin to explain how many arguments I&#x27;ve had over how and where AI is used when speaking with Artists. And that&#x27;s 100% expected. Not only has AI scraped every site on which this community has put down their roots and grown, but it has created mockingly hollow shells that wear their mask well enough to fool judges for art contests and the common average everyday art viewer.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point of contention I reach with my friends on this is whenver we try to examine the reality. There&#x27;s a reason why I started this post with words about the genie escaping its bottle. That&#x27;s to hammer into your head that we CANNOT turn back the clock.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put a badge in your bio saying &quot;Proudly Human Made&quot;. Holler up and down social media about how AI is actually super inaccurate and can&#x27;t be trusted for literally anything. Vow to only code with a notepad from now on and block anyone that has ever signed up for a Chat GPT account. None of these things change the reality that AI is here to stay. It will not and cannot go back into its cage. You can ban it, you can send every AI researcher and ML engineer to hell, you can break every server and gpu with hammers. But then it will go underground. Progress will continue without oversight and where you cannot see it. It will train on your data without you even knowing, which is far worse than looking you in the face as it scrapes the talent off of your palms.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look at how much I&#x27;ve had to write just to defuse the situation before it even starts! If you weren&#x27;t reined in from the edge yet, then you&#x27;re really not going to like what I say-you should use AI and get used to AI and love AI, it&#x27;s going to take over the entire process for pretty much every facet of professional life and if you can&#x27;t figure out how to wield the tool, then the tool will wield you.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whoops! Forgot to warn you!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;our-tools&quot;&gt;Our Tools&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I watch a very talented Game Developer titled &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;channel&#x2F;UC2U5mRfclG1Rrr1ztNkpGKA&quot;&gt;Royal Skies&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. He does tutorials without fluff or nonsense, mainly circling around Unreal Engine 4 &amp;amp; 5. As a Godot dev, I haven&#x27;t watched him as commonly as I used to, as the workflow between engines is far too different, but I did stumble onto a video of his that I have now lost in the annals of my Watch History. In it, he says that he is not a 3D artist because he wants to be. Art is just the means to an end. He learned art to achieve his creative vision. To bring the characters that he had in his head, to life.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to that philosophy, I agree whole-heartedly. Every vertex I place, every line I manipulate, every brush stroke on a canvas, and every line of code that built this website, was done to achieve a direct goal. As romantic as the idea is, I have far too many other hobbies to engage with and skills to develop to &quot;waste time&quot; doing any of this stuff just for the hehe hahas. Not that I don&#x27;t greatly enjoy what I do. I like woodworking, but you won&#x27;t see me chopping down a bunch of trees. I also enjoy leatherworking, but the only time you&#x27;re going to see me skinning an animal is after the nuclear fallout settles and my indoor crops were blighted, so I had to go out and kill rad-bison.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was young, I had all these grand visions and detailed documents about things I wanted to make and see made. Not just for games, but, books, engineering, metalworking, automobiles, the works. My inner world was and still is very vibrant and I always have that spark in me, maybe I&#x27;ll write about it some other time. My imagination was obviously too sophisticated for mortal minds to comprehend because my list is still largely incomplete today. These are things I have to tackle myself to see them fulfilled. I only have so much time on this mortal coil and I want to spend it enjoying myself and engaging in things that I think matter. Not a bunch of irrelevant bullshit that&#x27;s in-between me and that goal.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s my process of learning. Some people read text books. Some practice the same thing 10000 times. Some need a lecture or tutor to guide them along. I need a goal to achieve and whatever bullshit I get myself into along the way is just a part of my process. Every wall I hit is a wall to overcome. Only when I find the use and context of knowledge can I then apply it. I was one of those kids who didn&#x27;t study if you couldn&#x27;t tell. And I ate shit when I stopped caring about Math Class. It&#x27;s all about intent for me. Always has been, and that likely ain&#x27;t changing until I reach the age where I forget what my grand-kids look like.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&#x27;t ACTUALLY learn how to shade spheres by looking at balls under a lamp. I&#x27;ve picked up a shortcut in my head that says I need xyz colors in abc positions and then a contact shadow on the bottom.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#x27;t ACTUALLY know how the keyframes in CSS translate into machine code. I just know that if I work it a certain way, my elements will move along that trajectory.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photoshop has over 200 buttons and options. I have only ever used 20 of them at most.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blender has probably just as many, if not more. After making my shortcut list, with only 10 commands, I have never looked in another menu since.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you give me a fully stocked toolbox, I will empty the entire fucking box, then go about my life, only picking up tools and adding them when I truly need them. Emphasis on &lt;strong&gt;truly&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. If I can hammer in a screw, and achieve whatever joint I wanted to achieve that way, you better believe I will. Who the fuck are you to tell me to use a screwdriver?!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So where does AI come into the picture?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;jackhammer&quot;&gt;Jackhammer&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well that video was actually about AI, and Royal&#x27;s stance on it. It came down to him percieving it as a tool that can help him in his process. And considering how much I&#x27;ve said so far, you might&#x27;ve thought I agreed with him.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I was unsure for a long time.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AI wasn&#x27;t just a tool to me. It was the thing taking jobs that didn&#x27;t need to be taken. It ruined the mental health of the most sensitive people I know, creatives. Give me your time and teach me, for free, without breaks, without complaining, and iterate as many times as I ask you to. You can&#x27;t. But AI can. That wasn&#x27;t just some random shit to me, it mattered. And so, I rejected the entire concept of AI for a long time. But one day, I got stuck on something and like usual, I went searching for an answer on reddit, because as we all know, Google eats glue.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I could click on a single link, Google Gemini summarized an answer that it found across a series of 3 webpages.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It worked.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something clicked then. I was treating the entire AI cycle like a runaway carriage. A jackhammer that would rattle and throw anyone that put their hands on it, but that wasn&#x27;t the case. Have I ever said that programmers are the most insufferable motherfuckers I have ever met? Well it&#x27;s true. I used to wade through the misery of Stack Overflow, diving into 10 year old forum threads where the first reply is almost always &quot;Why do you want to do that?&quot; or something like &quot;It works on my machine&quot;. I&#x27;ve had the great privledge of speaking to these guys tell me, the artist, how something should be designed and what looked good when they have the aesthetic sense of a doorknob.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here I was, stuck on a problem in Angular 2, an ancient and forgotten relic of Front End Development, and Gemini had my problem wrapped up in a toneally neutral bow. It handed it to me and boom, it worked.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;ai-overdose&quot;&gt;AI Overdose&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I wasn&#x27;t so easily fooled. I&#x27;ve dodged Instagram, Vine, Tiktok, Youtube Shorts, and every other form of nonsense brainrot that the internet has tried to inflict upon me. I know the dangers of losing my critical thinking skills very well, and good lord does AI know how to tempt you. When used wrong, AI will give you answers, some which are just straight up lies, and if you don&#x27;t know what you are doing, it&#x27;s very easy to poison yourself on the magic pill.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When using AI, you have to know how and WHY its answer is the right answer. When it comes to many of these things, there&#x27;s almost always more than one way to skin a cat. Why did the AI choose this method? What are the others? Is this actually right? Is this best practice? Is this scalable? Modular? Can I reuse this solution? All these and more after the break.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where you will lose the most people who try to use AI. Those without a certain foundation of knowledge to draw from, often find themselves lost in the sauce, so to speak. They have no clue why 2 jigsaw pieces fit togather, but this ain&#x27;t about them!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-dirty-artist&quot;&gt;The Dirty Artist&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something something badaboom badapow and I found myself in a less extreme position. I&#x27;m still largely anti-ai on the surface, but I understand its uses and limits far more now.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Royal Skies described himself in that video as a &quot;Dirty 3D Artist&quot;. He knows retopo, doesn&#x27;t even need to use Zremesher. He knows anatomy, clothing, gear, rigging, animations, the full pipeline from end to end, but despite that, Royal Skies uses AI here and there to generate assets here and there. The weakness of 3D AI right now is the topology, but Zremesher trivializes this by a large amount. A 1 button solution. And if it cannot, then any 3D Artist worth their salt can take an afternoon and bang out a quad-draw session.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the 3D Artist that knows what they are doing, AI can be a very potent time-saver. I&#x27;ve seen demos for some program that does in-between frame interpolation and if I was an animator, I&#x27;d be shaking in my boots. With just a few key poses, AI can do a lot of this stuff by itself now, and if you thought it wasn&#x27;t going to get more advanced, that would be a terrible mistake.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Dirty Artist doesn&#x27;t have time to sit there and perfect their proportions. They don&#x27;t want to tinker around with a base mesh or re-target their character for the 1000th time. The Dirty Artist commissions the machine that was built from the blood and sweat of his peers, to make whatever it is that he needs. The Dirty Artist will clean up the output, make it presentable and technically feasible. He will fix the n-gons. He will add loops for enhanced animation flexing. He will redo those normal maps and rebake the heights.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Dirty Artist uses AI as a junior, as an assistant, as a co-pilot, and as a tool in his toolbox. He is not ruled by the tool, and if the tool breaks, he can do without. The Dirty Artist is just as competent as the Clean Artist and twice as fast. There&#x27;s no love in his work, just a cold and calculated taskmaster mindset. He doesn&#x27;t wax poetic or worry about it not being good enough. If it&#x27;s trash, he&#x27;ll tell the AI to make another, then take over from there.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Dirty Artist, to me, isn&#x27;t just an artist in 3D. They could be anything. Any field in which AI encroaches upon, writing, art, programming, service, academia, the Dirty Artist is not scared of what the AI could do to take take take. They are more interested in what the AI can give give give.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;m not a Dirty Artist, but I fear that guy. He&#x27;s likely going to be the future of the medium. The new way we interface with machines and the world. He&#x27;s on a train that I&#x27;m not sure should be leaving the station. The genie left the bottle and he went running after it with a ball gag &amp;amp; leash. If we don&#x27;t want to get left on Platform 9 &amp;amp; 3&#x2F;4s, perhaps we should do the same?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dunno.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, I&#x27;m gone. Gonna bump some MAVI and seach for some chains that will fit on my dumbells.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take it easy~ | Luther✌🏿&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>Player Sovereignty</title>
          <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Luther Gray</author>
          <link>https://otherheaven.net/blog/playeragency/</link>
          <guid>https://otherheaven.net/blog/playeragency/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://otherheaven.net/blog/playeragency/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;wave-sup&quot;&gt;👋🏿 Sup&#x27;&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post was going to be about something else, but when I went looking for photos of Random Encounter Design, I found &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;significant-bits.com&#x2F;revisiting-random-encounters&quot;&gt;someone&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; who took my words from my mouth in a fantastic breakdown of the design problem and solutions that Game Designers could use.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there are other things I could add like the purpose that encounters serve for the sake of Pacing and Tension, I decided to let it be and focus instead on a different subject. The schism in players that got us to this place where patience is seen as an uneeded and archiac fossil of older times (And by that I mean the 00&#x27;s).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;but-first-a-non-sequitur&quot;&gt;But first, a non sequitur&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#x27;s a lot that could be said about Minecraft, and infact I have indeed said &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;youtu.be&#x2F;VjYM7RcN__I&quot;&gt;a lot about Minecraft&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, but something that continues to stick in my mind is their design principals. In the first place, Game Development has notoriously been a walled garden of sorts. Perhaps a black box, if you like that phrasing better. If you didn&#x27;t have the contacts, then your insight was limited to speculation and feverishly favorable journalists who wouldn&#x27;t necessarily tell you everything. They wouldn&#x27;t want to lose their exclusive access after all.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything that we know about how these older games that inspired generations of players comes from translated interviews with skittish and sometimes intentionally vague developers on the other side of the Pacific. If they had any greater philosophy when creating any of these games or their systems, we certainly weren&#x27;t privy to them. Even now, with the reserved nature of Game Devs, you&#x27;ll find that they don&#x27;t really have much to say outside of their circles. There&#x27;s a &lt;em&gt;very&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; good reason for why that is, but I&#x27;m not getting into it with this post.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minecraft, is one of the few games out there where not only has it been de-compiled despite being in active development, but the creators, Mojang, have been open and transparent when addressing the vision they have for the game and the internal rules they go by when making pretty much anything. Some of the more jaded fans may argue this is because after Notch left and left a gaping hole in Minecraft that could only truly be filled by pleasing the hardcore fanbase. However &lt;strong&gt;once again&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; that&#x27;s not for this post.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What we&#x27;ve learned from Mojang&#x27;s design documents is that they hold this principal of what I&#x27;d call Player Sovereignty.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;blogImages&#x2F;distantHorizons.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Distant Horizons&quot; title=&quot;The Distant Horizons Mod&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a Creeper blows up, the player must be around to hear it. If a block is mined, it was mined with the player&#x27;s notice. If danger is afoot, then the Player was the one who walked into it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Minecraft, everything is because the player interacted with the world. The biggest factor controlling what happens to them and the experience they have, is what they choose to do. This creates a very powerful game hook because the player can&#x27;t simply wait for the magic to come and find them, they must meet the game half-way and go out to seek it. One of the biggest challenges of Game Design, getting the player invested, hit with an elegant and very large hammer.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;so-player-agency&quot;&gt;So, Player Agency&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agency is a funny hehe haha word that represents the player&#x27;s ability to choose. Commonly used in 12 hour video essays by Youtubers who spend 11 hours and 43 minutes of their runtime recapping the story, Player Agency is an important factor in what makes a video game &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; like a video game. This has nothing at all to do with Game Feel which is a combination of animation principals, screenshake, and sounds. Instead, the feeling is mental. A connection that drives immersion and motivates the player to keep their mind and emotions in the world rather than outside of it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trick with Player Agency is that this medium can be interacted with in so many different ways by so many people that creating a tailored Player Agency machine can turn into a bit of a nightmare on the end of developers. On the player-side the reward is faceted based on the type of player they are and what motivates them.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;blogImages&#x2F;playerTypes.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Player Types&quot; title=&quot;Quantic&amp;#39;s Player Types&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you think I was going into that bit on this post? You should know better by now!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point is, Player Agency is generally a good thing. Anything that brings your player deeper into the experience is a plus. However, around 2013 or so, there was a definite schism in the ways that developers went about achieving Player Agency. Around this time, CRPGs and Immersive Sims were considered dead genres. We were still walking through the haze of multi-million dollar Call of Duty games and annual releases of Assassin&#x27;s Creed.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This idea of Player Agency was tuned down into its most direct and comforting form. Player Sovereignty. This is why I said Player Agency is &lt;strong&gt;generally&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; a good thing. However, for some genres, when used in its most distilled form, it does nothing but make for a bland world. Yes, that NPC only dies when you kill them, but does that engage you? The cops only chase you in GTA after you upset the local population, but how many Cop Chases do you need before it becomes a chore? When did having the choice become exhausting?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why choose at all?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, such a question created a decade of gaming hell that I don&#x27;t need to summarize for anyone reading this and we just now crawled out of it like it was an Umbral Era in Final Fantasy XIV. So, players have been jaded and conditioned into believing that the old ways, no matter how flawed or how much they are the reason why those ways died. Assassin&#x27;s Creed and Call of Duty weren&#x27;t annual releases because it was funny. Players voted with their wallet. Gears of War didn&#x27;t get that gray black filter out of thin air. Players of the era wanted that. Shadow didn&#x27;t suddenly pull out a gun. Players drove that attitude era and the market replied with a siren-song, as it always does. But this isn&#x27;t the post for that either!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long story short, return to monkey or something of the sort.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;oh-yeah-i-forgot-about-random-encounters&quot;&gt;Oh yeah, I forgot about Random Encounters&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what happens when you have a direct affront to Player Agency knocking on your door, in the current year, after all you&#x27;ve been through over the past 10 years, with a pail in hand, not even willing to say Trick-or-Treat? Well, you close the door on it all together. I&#x27;d argue that&#x27;s what has happened to Random Encounters.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The general consensus seems to be that they are outdated and rotten from the inside out. Anything that takes control away from the player is a sin that needs to be burned at the stake. It goes without saying that I&#x27;m a fan of Random Encounters when used properly, but this isn&#x27;t a post about defending&#x2F;implementing Random Encounters. That other guy did that for me, images and all. I just thought it would be fun to dive into the context we have around this divide.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it&#x27;s worth remembering that just like players hate Random Encounters now, they will hate Cozy Games next. In other news, grass is green!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cya around~ | Luther✌🏿&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>The Joy of Creation</title>
          <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Luther Gray</author>
          <link>https://otherheaven.net/blog/thejoyofcreation/</link>
          <guid>https://otherheaven.net/blog/thejoyofcreation/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://otherheaven.net/blog/thejoyofcreation/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;here-s-a-test-post&quot;&gt;Here&#x27;s a Test Post&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This site was built with &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.getzola.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Zola SSG&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. I don&#x27;t know why I went for this instead of &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;gohugo.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Hugo&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. They seem equal in functionality and for my purposes, I didn&#x27;t even really need an SSG to be frank. It&#x27;s all just a bunch of HTML and CSS. The markdown stuff is neat but not super needed.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, this is just a test post. I don&#x27;t have the energy in me to write something proper yet, but I do intend to move some of my notes for game design and my art showcases to this site eventually. Promise! 😊&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And when I end a post, I&#x27;ll do something like&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bye~ | Luther✌🏿&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OOOO THAT&#x27;S GOOD THAT&#x27;S GOOD I&#x27;M SO GOOD YEAH YEAHH YEAH!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
